hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and if you need my
specialized training to help you improve
your listening then become a member at
patreon.com
listeningtime if you become a member
then you'll get my seminars where i
train you to listen more effectively and
understand native speakers when they
speak fast and if you become a listening
time family member you'll receive my
advanced podcast episodes which will
help you reach an advanced level of
listening okay today i'm going to
continue talking about american culture
this video will be a part 2 to the last
b-1 video i made
so let's jump right in and examine a few
more important elements of american
culture the first one i want to talk
about is the tendency for americans to
hold people and things to a high
standard what do i mean by this well
americans often demand excellence and
when we don't get it we often complain
for example when americans experience
sub-optimal customer service this can
leave an impact on them they might write
a negative review online about that
establishment and they probably won't
ever go there again if they don't have
to i'll be honest i have this tendency
as well i don't leave negative reviews
but when i receive bad service at a
store or restaurant i get annoyed i know
it's not great to have this reaction and
i'm trying to get better at it however
sometimes i can't help but get a little
ticked off when i'm paying for a service
and yet the worker is slacking off or
has a bad attitude so of course you can
imagine how frustrating it can sometimes
be for me to deal with workers at public
institutions
and most americans would agree with me
on this we demand excellence and we're
often disappointed when we don't get it
okay the next cultural element i want to
talk about is competition in the u.s
there's competition everywhere this
aspect of american culture has its
positives and negatives in terms of
economics science and technology this
competitive atmosphere has resulted in a
lot of good things there are many people
who want to create the best product or
they want to be the first one to
discover something new and so a lot of
advancement technology and wealth is
created in the us as consumers we love
the fact that companies compete with
each other to give us the best product
or service at the lowest price and it's
awesome to see experts compete to come
out with the newest game-changing
technology but of course this
competitiveness can sometimes be a
negative thing people can feel a ton of
pressure to be better than others and
they might feel inadequate if they don't
measure up so i think it's important to
maintain a healthy level of competition
without going overboard alright the last
cultural element i want to talk about is
a pretty funny one in the u.s many
people like big things a lot of
foreigners notice this really quickly
when they travel to the us for the first
time for example there are a ton of big
cars and trucks on the road and the
roads themselves are big also when you
order food at restaurants the portions
are usually bigger than portions in
other countries and a lot of people like
to buy things in bulk too which means
they buy huge boxes or packages of food
and other items and i think in general
the us feels really big because it has a
lot of wide open spaces so i guess you
could say that overall things are bigger
in america alright that's all for today
leave a comment and tell me if there are
any other cultural elements in the us
that you find interesting remember to
download my free listening time podcast
and click on the link below in the
description box to become a member so
that you can receive my specialized
training which will help you understand
native speakers and if you want to reach
an advanced level of listening then
become a listening time family member so
you can receive my advanced podcast
episodes also subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram i'll see you next time